Welcome to the Overview of Exceptional Customer Service Fundamentals.
An important part of selling in the Amazon store is providing exceptional customer service.
It is worth the investment because it results in positive seller ratings, word-of-mouth referrals,
and ultimately more sales.
We train Amazon Customer Service Associates to keep the following guidelines in mind on every single
contact with customers.
As sellers, you can follow the same to provide a positive customer service experience to your customers.
One, treat every customer as your friend.
Be friendly and polite.
Be your best professional self.
Show respect by being fair and honest.
Be upbeat, empathetic, and patient.
Deliver on promises.
Keep current on changes and aware of new information.
Approach the situation recognizing that each customer's need is unique.
Two, know your customer.
Listen to their problem and think through how it may impact them.
With email, use simple and direct language that is easy to understand.
Three, never guess.
Carefully evaluate each customer question and answer it.
Be precise and say with confidence only what you know is true and relevant.
Do not speculate.
When the answer is not available, say so in order to preserve customer trust.
Four, solve the problem.
Partner with customers to find the right solution that fits their unique needs.
Seek out and use available resources to make things right.
In the end, solving the problem is what matters most.
Three things you can do to improve your customer service are sending quality communications using
empathy and being efficient in your messages.
Remember, quality communication is conversational, efficient, helpful, personal, direct, friendly,
positive, simple.
Practicing these principles will help you deliver professional customer service every time.
The Oxford Dictionary defines empathy as the ability to understand and share the feelings of another.
In the context of customer service, this means striving to care for your customers in a considerate
manner where you put yourself in their shoes and then reinforce the feeling with action.
To practice empathy with your customers, consider the five A's of empathy.
Acknowledge, appreciate, assure, action, apologize.
Empathy fuels connection and allows you to partner with your customer.
Using empathy helps to build your customer's trust in your product or service.
Another way to improve customer service is to look for ways to make it more efficient.
You could establish a checklist to work through for every customer contact.
That way, your responses are thorough, considerate, consistent, and prompt.
Finally, when answering customer contacts, take care to avoid speculation about the cause or resolution
to any issue the customer is experiencing.
Use your tools and resources to research and answer the question asked.
Answering customer questions with information you know to be true further builds customer trust.
This wraps up our video with tips on how to provide exceptional customer service.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.